<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Israel Martins</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 18:53:30 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 18:53:30 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My experience with Flutter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I already have developed cross-platform apps in React Native, but a startup has offered a job for me but with requirement Flutter knowledge. I begin to study Flutter and, I have noticed some differences with React Native.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first thing that I realized was is the language, while the React Native uses JavaScript, the Flutter apps are implemented with Dart language. Who is accustomed to the JavaScript language and React framework will develop quickly, but the Flutter developers need to program a language that is not very popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The second thing is Flutter doesn’t have any tools like Expo from React Native, which allows testing apps through QR code. It’s a little complicated to test apps with Flutter because it needs to install Android Studio, and React Native doesn’t need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Although I speak more cons points, I continue using Flutter in my projects, and I either can develop in React Native. I consider the requests to my clients, but if I create a mobile app, I will build it in React Native.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/my-experience-with-flutter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/my-experience-with-flutter/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>FreeCodeCamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
FreeCodeCamp is a non-profit organization created by Quincy Larson that is made up of a learning web platform, forum and blog that intends to teach web development to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-platform&quot;&gt;Web Platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It is a learning web platform that teaches through the tasks that the students have to complete and still it trains them for interviews. If the person has any doubts, he is encouraged to search and to ask to other developers. Thus, It can simulate the professional progression of a developer.
&lt;br /&gt;
Currently, It offers six certificates: Responsive Web Design, Algorithms And Data Structures, Front End Libraries, Data Visualization, Apis And Microservices and Information Security And Quality Assurance.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;front-end-and-back-end&quot;&gt;Front-End and Back-End&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Basically, web development is taught in two parts, Front End and Back End.
&lt;br /&gt;
Front End is introduced with the languages HTML, CSS. It is also presented in frameworks and libraries like BootStrap, JQuery and React.
&lt;br /&gt;
The Back End section offers the concept of the version control with Git and Heroku cloud platform as a service (PaaS) for running applications. The students also train with NodeJS framework and MongoDB database program. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;projects&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
They also offer  hints of projects to develop and build and this way creates a portfolio. Firstly, it shows a project already done for the developer to base. Lastly, it lists several user stories for the developer to fulfill. The projects require the knowledge of the Front End/Back End frameworks to create a client-server interaction.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The platform allows me to know new technologies and patterns through interactive ways, to get in touch with the community and to build applications. I recommend the FreeCodeCamp to anyone that wants to program or to start in web development.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/freecodecamp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/freecodecamp/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How it all began</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Working in an IT job in a foreign country has always been my ambition. I was a computer engineer student and already know how to program. I searched for any jobs in my field through Linkedin. But the jobs I found required knowledge in certain web patterns and languages. To meet the requirements, I searched online platforms to learn programming languages and web frameworks.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;online-interactive-platforms&quot;&gt;Online interactive platforms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
CodeAcademy is an online interactive platform that offers several languages and frameworks that I can learn and program. FreeCodeCamp is another that I found to learn new languages and front-end/back-end patterns for web development and to create projects.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;CodeAcademy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blogs-and-sites&quot;&gt;Blogs and sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are many things around web programming that I did not know, thus I have begun to read several sites and blogs about front-end and back-end. I have gotten into the web development. I learned about new frameworks and patterns for front-end and back-end.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/&quot;&gt;Css-Tricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tableless.com.br/&quot;&gt;Tableless&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://willianjusten.com.br&quot;&gt;Willian Justen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After all this, I can develop several projects in my GitHub and create a portfolio. I get my first training in development. I continue to long for new jobs and leaving my country remains my goal.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/israelmarmar&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://israelmarmar.github.io/portifolio/&quot;&gt;Portifolio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/how-it-alll-began/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/how-it-alll-began/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About me</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;profile&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/14979578?s=460&amp;amp;v=4&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-me&quot;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Israel, I was born in Manaus, Amazonas and I am currently a computer engineering student at UFAM. I am also an IT trainee and a full stack developer. I have studied IT fundamentals at IFAM. Nowadays I am studying new frameworks and web technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skills&quot;&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Responsive Design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSS (Vannila, Sass, Bootstrap)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Javascript (ES6/7, NodeJS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React / Redux&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angular&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automation (Webpack, Npm)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Git (GitHub, GitLab)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MySQL - MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;contact&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/israelmarmar&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/israelmarquesmartins/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/isrmarmar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:israel_batista.am@hotmail.com&quot;&gt;E-mail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/about/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/about/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
